Mar 2019 - Jul 2019

SUMMARY

3+ years of professional front-end dev experience with a strong understanding of UI UX principles. My typical workflow involves user research, design strategy, and prototyping/building the product while iterating on the product based on the feedback from multiple stakeholders. I can create personas, storyboards, wireframes and mockups. My development expertise includes HTML, CSS, Java and JavaScript. I do have knowledge on software testing. I have strong debugging and problem solving skills with an interest for 3D/AR/VR game development.

SKILL SET

SKILLSEI	
Adobe CC	Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, InDesign, After Effects, Adobe XD, Adobe Premiere Cut Pro, Adobe Muse, Lightroom, Bridge, Adobe Audition
Code/ Languages	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, C#, Java
Database	MySQL, MongoDB, Couchbase
Web frameworks	Bootstrap, AngularJS, NodeJS, jQuery
Software testing	JMeter, JUnit, K6, Jasmine-Karma, RunScope, Swagger, Rancher
Design	Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign
Prototype	Justinmind, Sketch, Axure, Balsamiq, Mock Plus, Adobe XD
Communication	Slack, Microsoft Teams, Skype for Business, G-Suite, Agile
Others	Autodesk Maya, Unity 3D, GitHub, Jenkins, Keynote, Eclipse, VSCode, Sublime

WORK EXPERIENCE

Employer: Office Depot, Boca Raton, FL

Role: Developer Responsibilities:

> Design, develop, implement, support and maintain an e-commerce application based on business requirements, using approved techniques and coding standards for Java micro-services.

- Maintain the front-end layout using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery plugins.
- Participate in usability testing, design strategy and collaboration with research specialists on the client's requirements.
- Execute the code using Swagger/ RunScope and Rancher to find the error logs.
- Create REST APIs for internal and external endpoints using RunScope to test data (prod, pre-prod and dev env).
- Create tickets using JIRA ticketing system for error logs/ bug tracking while testing the services and pass it to the developer who was working on that particular service.
- Parameterize the N1QL query using simple, parameterized queries or prepared statements to avoid SQL injection. Migrate data from db2 to Couchbase.
- Develop the test cases using Mockito; document the code coverage using JUnit.
- Participate in SCRUM meeting every day following AGILE methodology.
- Use Jenkins for the deployment- Build-Test-Deploy.

Freelance project: Youngstar Club, Pokhara, Nepal

Role: Design + Develop

Responsibilities:

- Created a taxonomy (user interviews, sitemaps, card sorting, surveys) and prepared the documentation for the client.
- Built a site from scratch using bootstrap framework, XHTML, HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query and JavaScript.
- Used animate.css to give an animated look and feel for the site.
- Designed color palette and logo to reflect customer branding identity using Illustrator.
- Designed digital marketing materials for the social media promotions.
- Designed the wireframe and prototype (low fidelity) using Adobe XD and Balsamiq.
- Created a motion graphics for TVC using After Effects and Premiere Cut Pro.
- Used Slack to Communicate with the client to determine marketing and design vision, scopes of work, budgets and deliverable timeframes.

Employer: <u>Touro College</u>, New York, USA

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018

Role: IT Specialist (Graduate Assistant)

Responsibilities:

- Responded to email requests for technical assistance using service desk ticketing system (JIRA).
- Troubleshot and maintained hardware and software inventory.
- Built, Setup and deploy IT equipment for students.
- Installed, upgraded and optimized PC and network device hardware.
- Updated all the system with antiviruses in a timely manner.
- Volunteered in college workshop creating UI/UX design for Doodlematic Game.

Employer: Kaski Modernized Academy, Pokhara, Nepal

Jul 2014 - Apr 2016

Role: Website Manager/ Computer Science Teacher

Responsibilities:

- Managed the website using HTML, CSS under WordPress themes and plugins.
- Used Photoshop and Illustrator to create ID cards for students, certificates and banners for the events.
- Lectured students on practical knowledge of MS- Office, Adobe Photoshop and web design.
- Supported faculty members on technical issues while using the software, application or devices.
- Maintained the audio-video eLibrary by updating the contents using PHP and FileZilla.
- Prepared the marksheet for students and timesheet for teachers using Microsoft tools (Excel, Access).

INTERNSHIP

Employer: <u>VRBAR</u>, Dumbo, Brooklyn, NY Role: Virtual Reality Arcade operator

Dec 2017 - Feb 2018

Employer: <u>Last Door Solutions</u>, Kathmandu, Nepal

Feb 2012 - Jan 2013

Role: Junior Web Designer

EDUCATION

Master of Arts: Web Design and Multimedia

<u>Touro College Graduate School of Technology</u> - New York, NY [2016 - 2018]

Bachelor of Science: Multimedia Technologies

<u>Islington College - London Metropolitan University</u> - Kathmandu, Nepal [2011 - 2014]

Aug 2018 - Feb 2019